Under the Skin is a thriller, science fiction, drama
film directed by Jonathan Glazer.
A seductive stranger prowls the streets of Glasgow in search of
prey: unsuspecting men who fall under her spell.
Under the Skin is a 2013  science fiction film directed by Jonathan Glazer and written
by Glazer and Walter Campbell, based on the 2000 novel by Michel Faber.
It stars Scarlett Johansson as a female extraterrestrial disguised as a
human who preys on lone men in the evening hours in Scotland.
The film premiered at the Telluride Film Festival on 29 August 2013.
It was released in the United Kingdom on 14 March 2014,
and in other territories later in the year.
Glazer developed Under the Skin for over a decade.
He and Campbell pared it back from an elaborate, effects-heavy concept to a
sparse story focusing on an alien perspective of the human condition.
Most of the cast had no acting experience, and many
scenes were filmed with hidden cameras.
The film was a box-office failure, grossing $7.2
million on a budget of $13.3 million.
Under the Skin was widely acclaimed by critics for Glazer’s direction,
Johansson's performance, Landin’s cinematography, and Mica Levi's score.
It received numerous accolades and awards, was named the best film of the year by various critics and publications, appeared on
many best-of-the-decade lists, and was ranked 61st on the BBC's 100 Greatest Films of the 21st Century list.
It has subsequently been regarded as one of the best
films of the 2010s and the 21st century.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
scotland, edinburgh, scotland, alien, prowler.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.